aoi hoshi ni senritsu ga hashiru
a
o
i
ho
shi
ni
se
n
ri
tsu
ga
ha
shi
ru
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
kuroi arashi chikazuku toki
ku
ro
i
a
ra
shi
chi
ka
zu
ku
to
ki
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
kokoro no oku de mezameru HERO
ko
ro
no
o
ku
de
me
za
ru
HE
RO
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
tobitatsu no da furimukazu ni
to
bi
ta
tsu
no
da
fu
ri
mu
ka
zu
ni
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
DAGWON kagayake DAGWON
DA
G
WON
ka
ga
ya
ke
DA
G
WON
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Brave Command Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Dagwon... Shine on!! Dagwon!
다그온 빛나라!! 다그온
heiwa mamoru namae sa
he
i
wa
ma
mo
ru
na
ma
e
sa
The name that protects the peace
평화를 지키는 이름이다
DAGWON oretachi DAGWON
DA
G
WON
o
re
ta
chi
DA
G
WON
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
yume wa zettai watasanai
yu
me
wa
ze
t
ta
i
wa
ta
sa
na
i
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
afureru yuuki te ni shitai nara
a
fu
re
ru
yu
u
ki
te
ni
shi
ta
i
na
ra
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
tsuyoku tsuyoku yuujou shinjiru koto sa
tsu
yo
ku
tsu
yo
ku
yu
u
jo
shi
n
ji
ru
ko
to
sa
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
kizutsuku koto mo osore wa shinai
ki
zu
tsu
ku
ko
to
mo
o
so
re
wa
shi
na
i
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
mugendai no mirai wo egaku sono tame ni
mu
ge
n
da
i
no
mi
ra
i
wo
e
ga
ku
so
no
ta
me
ni
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
In front of the overwhelming power of Mado, Dagwon had a difficult fight in Mars.
화성에서의 사투에서 마도의 압도적인 힘에 다그온은 고전했다
En combined to form Super Fire Dagwon and shattered Mado at once with Lian and Gunkid.
또다시 슈퍼 파이어 다그온으로 합체한 엔은 라이안, 건키드와의 삼신일체 공격으로 마도를 분쇄한다
But, Sargasso, which is supposed to be empty, began a grave transformation.
하지만, 아무도 없을 터인 사르갓소가 심상치 않은 변형을 개시했다
Sargasso has...
사르갓소가…
Sargasso has transformed!
사르갓소가 변형했잖아?!
No way! What the heck is going on?!
말도 안돼! 대체 어떻게 된 거야?!
Are there still aliens inside Sargasso?
사르갓소엔 아직 우주인이 남아있는 건가?!
That's impossible! Mado is dead! The aliens are supposed to be annihilated!
말도 안돼! 마도는 죽었어! 우주인은 전멸했을 거라구!
But Sargasso is actually heading toward Earth!
하지만 실제로 사르갓소는 지구로 향하고 있습니다!
What the heck is going on inside?!
저 안에서 무슨 일이 일어나고 있는 거지?
Lian...
라이안…
As expected...
역시…
According to the design by the Space Police Organization, no such transformation system exists!
우주 경찰 기구의 설계에 저런 변형 시스템은 존재하지 않습니다
Ryu, please move En to Dag Base. We'll stop Sargasso from going any further.
류, 넌 엔과 다그 베이스로 옮겨줘 우린 사르갓소의 전진하지 못하도록 막을게
Be careful.
조심해
Rai and I will follow in Dag Base too.
나와 라이도 다그 베이스로 뒤쫓아갈게
I'll take a look at that. You stay calm and wait.
잠깐 상황을 보고 오마 얌전히 기다려라
Let's go.
가자…
To Sargasso!
사르갓소로!
Sargasso Explodes
사르갓소 대폭발
Super Life-form Genocide
Appears
초생명체 제노사이드
등장
Super Chaining Fusion!
초중련합체
(超重連合體)
Super Liner Dagwon!
슈퍼 라이너 다그온
It's big! It's way too big!
크다!
허벌나게 크구만!
What? It's just an oversized rock!
뭐야, 그냥 돌덩어리일 뿐이잖아
Alright, let's attack that face!
좋아, 저 얼굴을 공격한다!
What?!
아니?!
I got you!
잡았다~
Stop!
거기 서!
Please forgive me!
이, 이제 그만 봐줘
What did I do?
내가 뭘 했다고 이래?!
You guys are distracting the disciplines!
너희들은 풍기를 어지럽히고 있어!
Even if you say so...
그런 말 해봤자…
Hey, it's grandma!
앗, 할머니다!
Hey! Grandma!
여어~ 할머니~
Hey! Don't call my grandma so casually!
야! 우리 할머니 멋대로 부르지마!
What are you talking about?
무슨 소리야?
She's my grandma!
우리 할머니라니까!
Grandma!
-할머니~
-할머니~~
Please respond!
응답하세요!
Senpais, please respond!
선배들, 응답해 주세요!
It doesn't work. The senpais are not responding.
틀렸습니다 선배들의 응답이 없습니다
-Move as fast as you can.
-Yes, sir!
-전속력으로 가자
-네!
It doesn't seem to be attacking any time soon.
공격해 올 낌새는 없군요
How is their reaction in Sargasso?
사르갓소 내에 애들의 반응은?
No detection.
관측 불능
What should we do?
어떻게 하실 겁니까?
Ryu, Rai!
류, 라이!
There... Sargasso...
저, 저기…
사르갓소가…!
The door is open!
문이 열렸잖아?!
It seems that we're invited into Sargasso.
아무래도 우리는 사르갓소에게 초대받은 것 같군
Senpai...
선배…
Are you scared?
무섭니?
No!
아니오!
...yes.
…네
Me too.
나도 마찬가지야
-Did you turn on Dag Base's autopilot?
-It's turned on.
-다그 베이스의 자동 조종은?
-전환해 두었습니다
It will automatically follow Sargasso.
사르갓소를 자동 추적할 겁니다
Alright. Let's go!
좋아, 가자!
-Yes, sir!
-네!
-응!
En. Take care of Dag Base for a moment.
엔, 잠시 다그 베이스를 부탁한다
We're now entering Sargasso. We'll come back before you wake up.
우리는 사르갓소에 돌입할 거야
네가 깨어날 때까진 돌아올게
There's no abnormalities here either.
이곳도 이상 없군요
I was originally created in Sargasso, so...
원래 난 사르갓소에서 만들어졌으니까
I-I'm not scared...
무, 무섭지…
No, I'm scared!
역시 무서워!
Wait!
기다려---!
These are imitation black hole devices. More than 5000 aliens were sealed inside these.
유사 블랙홀 장치 이 안에 5000명이나 되는 우주 죄수를 봉인했던 거군
There is no life reaction.
생명 반응 0
Currently, all the space inside of the imitation black holes are empty.
현재 유사 블랙홀 안쪽은 모두 비어 있습니다
Calm down, Gunkid!
진정해, 건키드
There are numerous cracks due to space storms. Be careful.
우주 폭풍의 영향으로 이곳저곳 금이 가 있으니까요 조심해야 해요 으, 응…
Cleaning- Cleaning-
청소-청소-
There are enemies! Enemies! There!
있다, 있어!
적이야, 적!
Cleaning- Cleaning- Cleaning-
청소-청소-청소-
They are Sargasso's administration and cleaning robots.
사르갓소의 관리 겸 청소용 로봇이예요
Knowing that they are active... it might mean that the main computer is still active too!
이녀석이 움직이고 있다는 건… 중앙 컴퓨터가 아직 살아있을지도 모르겠군요
This is not good. It reconstructed itself as it wanted.
이거 난처하군 멋대로 이렇게 개축해 버리다니…
-What is this place?
-The meeting place of aliens.
-이곳은?
-우주인들의 집합소야
Is anybody there? If then, show yourself!
누구 있나?! 있다면 모습을 드러내라!
Maybe all the prisoners in Sargasso are gone, with Mado as the last one.
역시 마도를 끝으로 사르갓소의 죄수는 전멸한 게…
You are correct.
그 말대로야
Dag Turbo! Dag Armor!
다그 터보, 다그 아머!
Dag Wing! Dag Drill!
다그 윙, 다그 드릴!
Lian! You're alright!
라이안, 무사했구나!
Wait!
기다려!
Something's not right.
낌새가 이상해
No need to worry.
걱정할 필요 없다
The prisoners of Sargasso are all gone.
사르갓소의 죄수는 전멸했어
But the crisis upon the Earth is still here.
하지만 지구의 위기는 사라진 게 아니야
Including Three Warugaia Brothers, the aliens were simply puppets.
와르가이아 3형제를 비롯해 죄수들은 모두 단순한 꼭두각시였지
Puppets?
꼭두각시?
The Earth Hunt of Sargasso.
사르갓소에 의한 지구 사냥
It was being done by a being with an unknown sentience that no prisoner had ever noticed.
그건 죄수들도 눈치채지 못한 어느 의지를 가진 존재가 진행하고 있었던 것입니다
What is that unknown sentience?
어느 의지란 뭐지?!
A being that has transcended our concepts.
우리 개념을 월등히 초월한 존재
In other words, a super life-form.
다시말해 초생명체지
Super life-form?
초생명체?!
Senpai!
선배!
What happened?
우리는 대체…?
What is this place?
여긴 어디죠?
Dag Shadow! Dag Thunder!
다그 섀도우에, 다그 선더?
Gunkid?! Why are you here?
건키드?
어째서 너까지!
We must have rushed into Sargasso and...
우리는 분명히 사르갓소 안에 돌입해서…
and...
돌입해서…
Shadow Shuriken!
섀도우 수리검!
Dag Shadow?!
다그 섀도우?!
We are being watched by someone.
우리는 누군가에게 감시당하고 있어!
Sargasso...
사르갓소…
This didn't work either.
이것도 틀렸나…
What should we do? We cannot use the main computer like this.
어떻게 하실 겁니까? 이대론 중추 컴퓨터를 쓸 수 없습니다
Alright, I'll destroy this door then!
좋아, 내가 이 문을 부숴주마!
No way... There's no way it could open by itself!
이럴 수가… 멋대로 열리다니, 있을 수 없어요!
This is...
이건…?!
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
Original Korean Subtitles by Jaebari (재바리)
Translated to English by Subdivers
Checked by Great Exkaiser103
자막 원본(번역): 재바리
수정: Subdivers
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
용자지령
다그온
How could this thing be stuck in the main computer?!
이런 게 중앙 컴퓨터에 박혀 있었다니!
Dagwon gentlemen.
다그온 제군
Who's there?!
누구냐?!
My name is Genocide.
내 이름은 제노사이드
Genocide?!
제노사이드?!
The absolute perfection.
절대적이며 완벽한 존재
Where? Where are you?!
어디냐?!
어디 있느냐?!
It's the meteorite! In the center of it!
운석입니다!
운석 중심에!
Is this bastard also an alien of Sargasso?!
이자식, 사르갓소의 죄수인가?!
No, it isn't! Such a life form isn't in the records!
아니예요! 저런 생명체는 기록에 없습니다!
Who are you?! What's your objective?!
넌 누구냐?!
목적은?!
Lower life forms with bodies like you might not be able to understand me at all.
너희들, 육체를 가진 하등한 생물이 나를 이해하는 것은 도저히 불가능할지도 모르겠군
I've been roaming through numerous galaxies for billions of years. And...
나는 수억년이라는 세월을 거쳐 수많은 우주를 방랑해왔다 그리고…
By chance, I found a dish named Sargasso, which I could attach to.
우연히 나는 사르갓소라는 그릇을 손에 넣어 옮겨 탈 수 있게 되었다
For the bigger objective, I've used the prisoners to invade the Earth and
더욱더 큰 목적을 위해 나는 죄수들을 지쿠 침략에 이용하고
commanded Three Warugaia Brothers to kill you Dagwons.
와르가이아 3형제에게 너희들 다그온의 말살을 명령했다
But they didn't notice me at all.
녀석들은 나의 존재를 눈치채지 못했지만 말이다
Why?! Why are you aiming at the Earth?!
어째서냐?! 어째서 넌 지구를 노리는 거냐?!
-To merge with the Earth.
-Merge?!
-지구와의 융합
-융합?!
Right.
그렇다
I'll move to the Earth and be born as a new planet.
지구라는 그릇에 옮겨 타 나는 새로운 별로 다시 태어날 것이다
What?!
-뭐야?!
-뭐라고?!
No way! If that happens, the Earth will be...
그럴 수가! 그렇게 되면 지구는 대체…?!
Probably just like Sargasso, both the Earth and earthlings will be controlled by him!
필시 사르갓소와 같이 지구도 지구인도 녀석의 마음대로…!
Don't make fools out of us! As long as we Dagwon exist, you're not going to do as you want!
웃기지 마라! 우리 다그온이 있는 한 멋대론 못한다!
That's right!
그 말대로다!
Eat this!
받아라!
How's that?!
어떠냐?!
How impudent.
어리석구나
Dag Armor?!
다그 아머?!
What are you doing, Dag Armor?!
무슨 짓이야, 다그 아머?!
Gunkid?!
건키드?!
It's that bastard! They're being controlled by that bastard!
저녀석이야! 녀석에게 조종당하고 있는 거야!
My body is...
몸이 멋대로…
...moving by itself!
움직이고 있어!
Fight your comrades.
동료끼리 싸우거라
My name is Genocide.
나의 이름은 제노사이드
The absolute perfection.
절대적이며 완벽한 존재
According to research from the observatories of the world and the UN,
각국 천문대 및 UN의 조사 결과
the big object approaching Earth is identified as an artificial structure made by aliens.
현재 지구에 접근중인 거대한 물체는 우주인에 의한 인공적인 건조물이라고 판정
Repeat!
반복하겠습니다
Aliens are invading us!
우, 우주인의 대 습격이다!
What is Dagwon doing?!
다그온은 대체 뭘 하고 있는 거야?
They probably ran away, scared of the aliens!
우주인이 무서워서 지구에서 도망쳤겠지!
Why you-!
이놈!
I will not forgive anyone that defames Dagwon!
다그온을 나쁘게 말하는 놈은 내가 가만 안 둘 거야!
What's so great about Dagwon? The Earth is on the verge of ending!
다그온은 무슨 얼어죽을… 지구는 이제 끝장이라구!
Please stop.
그만둬
But... I can't accept this!
그치만 말이야… 분하단 말이야!
Gaku...
가쿠…
-Hey, they say we're all going to die!
-Shut up. Just keep your mouth closed!
-이봐, 우리 다 뒈진다네?
-시끄러, 닥치고 있어!
-What? Do you wanna fight, you brat?!
-Yeah, let's fight, you drunkard!
-뭐야? 한판 뜰까, 이자식!
-그래 한판 붙자, 주정뱅이 자식아!
Everyone, pleast listen to me!
여러분, 들어주세요!
Dagwon is fighting for the Earth with all their power!
다그온은 지금 지구를 위해서 필사적으로 싸우고 있어요!
Maria...
누나…
Please don't give up to the last moment! Keep calm or it's all over!
끝까지 포기하지 말아요! 냉정함을 잃으면 끝이예요!
Please! Believe in Dagwon!
부탁이예요! 다그온을 믿어주세요!
New information has arrived.
새로운 정보가 들어왔습니다
The UN has decided to use the final missile on the object that's approaching Earth.
지구에 접근중인 우주인의 건조물에 대하여 UN은 최종 미사일의 사용을 결정했습니다
Maria!
누나---!
Gaku!
가쿠---!
It will be dangerous, so please hurry and take shelter in the subway or in the underground road.
위험이 예상되므로 시민 여러분께선 지하철 혹은 지하도 속으로 신속히 피난해 주십시오
It will be dangerous! Please hurry up and take shelter!
위험이 예상됩니다 시민 여러분께선 신속히 피난해 주십시오!
The missile is about to be launched!
최종 미사일이 발사됩니다!
Dagwon is...
다그온이…
Dagwon is still fighting!
다그온이 아직 싸우고 있단 말이야!
En here!
여기는 엔!
Sargasso is in front of the Earth!
사르갓소는 지구 코앞까지 왔어!
Respond! Everyone!
응답해, 얘들아!
Something has definitely happened inside Sargasso.
역시 사르갓소 안에서 무슨 일이 생긴 거야!
At this rate, the Earth will be...!
이대론 지구가…!
Did you feel my power?
나의 힘을 느꼈느냐!
Be one with me.
나와 동화하자
Move!
움직여…
Move, you punk!
아자식, 움직여라!
Even Geki moved this! I should be able to as well! Move!
게키 녀석도 움직이게 했어! 나도 할 수 있을 거야! 움직여라!
Move! Move, Dag Base!
움직여! 움직이라고, 다그 베이스!
Please, Dag Base!
부탁해, 다그 베이스!
The Earth... Our Earth is in a pinch!
지구가… 우리 지구가 위험하단 말이야!
10 minutes until the launch of the final missile!
최종 미사일 발사까지 앞으로 10분!
Anyone on the ground, please take shelter right now!
땅 위에 남아있는 사람은 어서 빨리 신속히 피난해 주십시오!
Please stop... there is...
그만둬… 저곳에는…
There is... En and...
저곳에는…
엔이… 있는데…
En!
엔-----!
Move!
움직여라-----!
Super Merging Fusion!
초융합합체
(超融合合體)
D- damn you... Are we done?
이, 이놈…
이젠 여기까진가!
What's going on?
무슨 일이지?!
Could it be...?
설마?!
What the-?!
뭐지?!
En senpai has...
엔 선배가…
mobilized Dag Base!
다그 베이스를 움직이고 있습니다!
Cleaning- Cleaning-
청소-청소-
En senpai! Here we are!
엔 선배, 여기예요!
En!
엔!
Understood!
알았어!
Let's go!
간다---!
Sorry to keep you waiting, everyone!
오래 기다렸지, 얘들아!
A shudder runs over the blue planet
푸른 지구에 전율이 흐른다
This is...
이건…?!
It's the time the dark storm approaches
검은 폭풍이 닥쳐오는 순간
Farewell, Sargasso!
작별이다, 사르갓소!
It's as if a hero is awakening on the inside
마음 속의 눈을 뜬 영웅들이여
Fly away and don't look back!
뒤돌아보지 말고 날아가라
Dagwon! We are Dagwon!
다그온 우리는 다그온
We will never hand over our dream
꿈은 절대로 넘겨줄 수 없다
To grab the overflowing courage
넘쳐흐르는 용기를 거머쥐고 싶다면
We believe in our friendship firmly
우리 우정을 굳게 믿는 거다
We are not afraid of getting hurt
상처입는 것도 두렵지 않아
Right before we launched the final missile, the structure of the alien has exploded, and the launch has been canceled!
최종 미사일 발사 직전 우주인의 건조물은 대폭발, 미사일 발사는 중지되었습니다
In order to reach that infinite future!
무한대의 미래를 그려내기 위해서라면
Everyone! The Earth is... the Earth has been rescued!
여러분, 지구는… 지구는 구원받았습니다!
It's Dagwon! Dagwon has succeeded!
다그온이야! 다그온이 성공한 거야!
Thank you, Dagwon.
고마워, 다그온…
Thank you...
고마워…
En...
엔…
It's over.
모두 다 끝났구나
Mission accomplished! Return to Earth!
임무 완료!
지구에 귀환한다!
My name is Genocide.
나의 이름은 제노사이드
The absolute perfection.
절대적이며 완벽한 존재
The sun suddenly called me
태양이 갑작스레 나를 불러내서
taiyou ga fui ni ore wo izanau
To come to the blue sea
푸르게 비치는 바다로 만나러 갔지
aoku sukitooru umi ni ai ni kita
The ripples are coming and going
밀려왔다 돌아가는 잔물결
yosete wa kaesu sazanami
An endless melody
멈추지 않는 멜로디
tomaru koto nai MELODY
To keep that shape for eternity
그 모습을 영원히 유지할 수 있도록
sono sugata towa ni tsunagu you ni
I'll follow the fate of the dream
꿈의 행방을 뒤쫓아 갈 거야
oikakete yuku yo yume no yukue
Sparkling far away
멀리서 반짝이던
tooku kirameita
A Prism in the Wind
바람 속의 프리즘
kaze no naka no PRISM
Yuusha Shirei
Dagwon
Preview for Next Episode
용자지령
다그온
차회예고
Genocide is alive! That bastard stole Fire Jumbo and began to fuse with the Earth!
제노사이드가 살아있었어! 녀석, 파이어 점보를 훔쳐 지구와의 융합을 개시했어!
Unforgivable! I'll take it down!
용서 못해! 어쨌든 내가 해치우겠어!
You can't! If you go nearby, you'll be fused too!
말도 안돼! 가까이 가면 너도 융합되어버려!
If the Earth is controlled, then it's no different!
지구가 전부 지배당하면 다를 바 없잖아!
I have only one thing I can do by now!
이렇게 되면 방법은 하나밖에 없어!
What are you going to do, En? Stop!
어쩔 셈이냐, 엔?! 그만둬!
Next time on Yuusha Shirei Dagwon! Burn! En, the Brave of Flame!
다음회 용자지령 다그온
타올라라! 불꽃의 용자 엔
I'll go! This is the youth!
난 가겠어! 이게 바로 청춘이다!
Burn! En, the Brave of Flame
타올라라! 불꽃의 용자 엔